

Eyad Alhudhaif

Corporate Finance

- ▶ 08/31/2021 in Columbia, SC
- Saudi
- Unmarried



Skills

Programming: 5+ yrs.

SAS, STATA, Python

Webscraping 3+ yrs.

Arabic Native

English Fluent

Education

May, 2014

Scott College of Business, Indiana State University

MBA - Finance

Overall GPA: 3.94/4

June, 2010

King Saud University

B.S., Business Admin. - Financial Management

Overall GPA: 4/5

Biography

Eyad Alhudhaif is currently a PhD Candidate at the University of South Carolina. His research interests inculde Corporate Finance, Capital Structures, and Debt Maturity Structures. His recent work centers around textual analysis of corporate financial disclosures and its relation to corporate decisions.

Work Experience

Research Assistant

08/2015 - today

Darla Moore School of Business University of South Carolina

Assisted the following faculties with research related tasks; Dongmei Li, Sergey Tsyplakov, and Matthew Souther. Tasks include webscraping, preliminary analysis, literature review, and essay comments. Additionally, I assisted Eric Powers in building a Monte Carlo simulation for his class assignment for several academic semesters.

AACSB Assistant Coordinator

05/2014 - 05/2015

Scott College of Business Indiana State University

Worked with the business college to document and insure that faculties' intellectual contributions meet AACSB's requirements for the five year accreditation report.

Teaching Experience

Investment Analysis & Portfolio Management (FINA469)

05/2019 - 07/2019

Darla Moore of Business University of South Carolina

Summer I Course; Number of students: 12; Evaluation score: 4.55

Investment Analysis & Portfolio Management (FINA469)

07/2017 - 08/2017

Darla Moore of Business University of South Carolina

Summer II Course; Number of students: 19; Evaluation score: 4.26

Business Statistics I (BUS205)

08/2014 - 12/2014

Scott College of Business Indiana State University

Adjunct Instructor; Number of students: 30; Evaluation score: 3.77

Interests

- Cooking
- Travel
- ▶ Pool (Billiards)

Contact

- Columbia, SC, USA
- \Box +1(206) 718-2424
- ieyada@live.com
- Personal Website
- in ieyada
- @iEya d
- github.com/ieyada

Working Papers

- Alhudhaif, Eyad. (2021). "The Asymmetry Between Growth Opportunities and Debt Maturity Structure". Working Paper.
 - https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3906487.
 - Using the recent public health pandemic (COVID-19) as a laboratory experiment, I find evidence of an asymmetrical relation between a firm's debt maturity structure choice and its growth opportunities. Firms with high pre-pandemic exposure to growth-inducing factors obtained from 10-K filings have increased debt maturity and are more likely to exercise a call on their callable bonds, while firms with high pre-pandemic exposure to growth-reducing factors are null in taking any actions to adjust their debt maturity structure. Further, the increase in debt maturity following exogenous changes in growth opportunities suggests a unique type of change in firms' growth options following the recent pandemic, supporting the arguments proposed by Diamond and He (2014) and Childs, Mauer, and Ott (2005).
- Alhudhaif, Eyad. (2016). "Corporate Payouts Under Economic Policy Uncertainty".
 Working Paper.
 - Using a sample of all public firms in the U.S. between 1985 and 2015, I examine the relation between firm behavior in payout policies under changes in the level of economic policy uncertainties, both total and individual components of payouts; dividends and open market share repurchases. Using the EPU index and its components developed by Baker et al. (2016), I find payout programs tend to respond differently depending on which component of the uncertainty changes. A persistent negative relationship exists between the level of uncertainty in government spending (GSU) and firms' average level of dividends, share repurchase, and total payout.

Involvements & Awards

- Member of the investment club Indiana State University, (01/2013-12/2013)
- Secretary of the MBA Association Indiana State University, (01/2013-05/2014)
- Member of the Association for Operations Management, University of Indianapolis Student Chapter (2013)
- Beta Gamma Sigma award Indiana State University (2014)
- APICS Great Lakes District Student Case Competition, ranked 4th Indiana State University (2014)
- Outstanding Student Award University of Washington (2011)

10th September 2021	
	Eyad Alhudhaif